# **Ammad Umar**

# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email: ammad.umar@outlook.com
Website: ammadumar.netlify.app
LinkedIn: ammad-umar000
Github: ammadUmarDev
Hackerrank: ammad\_umar

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I'm a dedicated, and target-oriented individual with overall 2+ years of professional experience as a developer. I believe I am capable of quickly becoming an asset due to my urge to continually learn and acquire new skills. I'm looking for a contributor role where I can be part of a collaborative team, learn new tools and technology, and gain experience as a software engineer.

# SKILL SET

#### **LANGUAGES**

- Python
- Dart
- Java
- C++
- HTML
- CSS (SASS, LESS)
- JavaScript (ES6)
- Kotlin
- · Assembly x86

# **TOOLS & TECHNOLOGIES**

- jQuery
- · React JS (incl Hooks, Redux, Router)
- Bootstrap 4
- SQL DB (MySQL, Oracle, SQLite)
- NoSQL DB (Firebase)
- Message Queues (RabbitMQ)
- Cloud Solutions (GCP)
- API Development (Flask REST)
- Reactive Web Application Development
- Flutter App Development
- · WordPress Development
- · Containerization ( Docker )

#### INDUSTRY KNOWLEDGE

- Netlify
- · Agile Methodologies
- · Version Control with Git
- · Object-Oriented Programming
- · Data Mining and Machine Learning

#### OTHER

- Detail Oriented
- Self-Starter
- Willingness to learn
- · Eagerness to collaborate

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- · Machine Learning by Stanford University
- Crash Course on Python by Google Cloud
- Version Control with Git by Atlassian
- · SQL for Data Science by UC
- Python (Basic) | HackerRank
- Problem Solving (Basic) | HackerRank

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### **Software Engineer Intern**

2vec Consulting | Jul 2020 - Sep 2020

- Semantic search with approximate nearest neighbors and text embeddings
- Development of InVigil Chrome extension using web RTC (ML, Python, NLP, thereTensorflow, Flask)

# **Research and Development Intern**

Information System Research Lab | Feb 2020 - Nov 2020

- R&D of an optimized delivery scheduling and routing system w.r.t domain constraints
- Deployment of REST API on Google Cloud Platform (ML, NN, Python, Scikit-Learn, Flask, SQLite, and RabbitMQ)

## **Project Intern**

Telenor Microfinance Bank Limited | Jun 2019 - Dec 2019

- Development of 'Easypaisa' brand web application
- Load time optimization, Google analytics, and Google maps integration
- API development (Cashpoint Locator) (HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, WordPress, PHP, and MySQL)

# **PROJECTS**

# **Ugao.pk Android/IOS Application**

Ecommerce mobile application for agriculture industry (Flutter, Dart, Firebase)

#### SentiMix Hindi-English

Artificial Intelligence Course 2020

Predict the sentiment of a given code-mixed tweet. (Python)

#### **Metro Cash and Carry Data Warehouse**

Data Warehouse Course 2020

Implementing MetroCC DWH using hybrid join and run OLAP queries (Java)

# Flight Data Prediction and Analysis System

Data Mining Course 2020

Analyze, visualize flight dataset and predict delays. (Python)

## Research Collaboration Graph and Maximum Spanning Tree

Algorithm Analysis and Design Course 2020

An optimized approach for creating a maximum spanning tree. (Python)

### **Udhaar Android/IOS Application**

Human Computer Interaction Course 2020

Money lending manager app (Flutter, Dart, Firebase)

# E.R.I.M.S Android/IOS Application

Software Engineering Course 2020

Event registration and information management system built for NUCS. (Flutter, Firebase)

#### Soduko Game

Operating Systems Course 2019

Soduko puzzle solver implementing core OS concepts e.g. multithreading. (C++)

# **EDUCATION BACKGROUND**

Bachelor of Computer Science | Class of 2021

FAST - National University of Computer and Emerging Sciences